Prologue UP148
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Prologue
1945 -- 2006
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Department of Drama and Dance
UP148
1.0 Linear Feet
2 Volumes
Arrangement
This collection is organized into one series.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains issues of Prologue. (All that is past is) Prologue is published three times a year by the Department of Drama and Dance to coincide with departmental productions directed by faculty.
Biographical / Historical
The Department of Drama and Dance formally came into existence on September 1, 1983. The Department of Drama absorbed the Dance Program which had been part of the Department of Physical Education to create the newly formed department. Professor Sherwood Collins, who had been the Chair of the Department of Drama remained as the head of the newly expanded department. Associate Professor Alice Trexler who had been at the helm of the Dance Program remained as its director after the formation of the new department had been officially completed.
The Department of Drama and Dance articulated information about the Department in the Bulletin of Tuft University for the academic year 1984-1985 as follows, "Through the study of drama and theater arts, the student can cultivate an understanding and appreciation of one of Western society's main civilizing forces; develop powers of intellect, imagination, emotion, and vocal and bodily expressiveness, as well as standards of good taste and workmanship; and gain a sound foundation for later pursuit of interests in this field". Regarding the Dance Program, the Bulletin stated, "The objectives of the Tufts dance program are to acquaint the student with both dance technique and dance theory within the realm of a liberal arts education".
The Department of Drama and Dance offers graduate programs leading to a Master of Arts as well as a Doctor of Philosophy.
Dance is a component of the Department of Drama and Dance, operating within the liberal arts philosophy with beginning to advanced courses. Events vary by semester, including informal presentations of faculty/student/guest work. Creativity and critical thinking are stressed in classes. The program serves the liberal arts goals rather than having a conservatory orientation even though several or more of our courses offer opportunities for students to continue with advanced skills. Modern dance is the core curricular element along with several non-western forms offered during the year.
- Prologue, 1945 -- 2006; 1945 -- 2004; UP148.001; 1.0 Linear Feet; 2 Volumes
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains issues of (All that is past is) Prologue, which is published three times a year by the Department of Drama and Dance to coincide with Departmental productions directed by faculty.
  Arrangement
  This series is arranged chronologically.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Open for research.
  - December, 1945 -- 1946; UP148.001.001.00001 (Box Volume 1)
  - January, 1945 -- 1946; UP148.001.001.00002 (Box Volume 1)
  - April, 1945 -- 1946; UP148.001.001.00003 (Box Volume 1)
  - May, 1945 -- 1946; UP148.001.001.00004 (Box Volume 1)
  - November, 1946 -- 1947; UP148.001.001.00005 (Box Volume 1)
  - January, 1946 -- 1947; UP148.001.001.00006 (Box Volume 1)
  - March, 1946 -- 1947; UP148.001.001.00007 (Box Volume 1)
  - May, 1946 -- 1947; UP148.001.001.00008 (Box Volume 1)
  - November, 1947 -- 1948; UP148.001.001.00009 (Box Volume 1)
  - January, 1947 -- 1948; UP148.001.001.00010 (Box Volume 1)
  - April, 1947 -- 1948; UP148.001.001.00011 (Box Volume 1)
  - May, 1947 -- 1948; UP148.001.001.00012 (Box Volume 1)
  - October, 1948 -- 1949; UP148.001.001.00013 (Box Volume 1)
  - January, 1948 -- 1949; UP148.001.001.00014 (Box Volume 1)
  - March, 1948 -- 1949; UP148.001.001.00015 (Box Volume 1)
  - May, 1948 -- 1949; UP148.001.001.00016 (Box Volume 1)
  - October, 1949 -- 1950; UP148.001.002.00001 (Box Volume 2)
  - November, 1949 -- 1950; UP148.001.002.00002 (Box Volume 2)
  - December, 1949 -- 1950; UP148.001.002.00003 (Box Volume 2)
  - April, 1949 -- 1950; UP148.001.002.00004 (Box Volume 2)
  - October, 1950 -- 1951; UP148.001.002.00005 (Box Volume 2)
  - December, 1950 -- 1951; UP148.001.002.00006 (Box Volume 2)
  - March, 1950 -- 1951; UP148.001.002.00007 (Box Volume 2)
  - April, 1950 -- 1951; UP148.001.002.00008 (Box Volume 2)
  - October, 1951 -- 1952; UP148.001.002.00009 (Box Volume 2)
  - December, 1951 -- 1952; UP148.001.002.00010 (Box Volume 2)
  - March, 1951 -- 1952; UP148.001.002.00011 (Box Volume 2)
  - April, 1951 -- 1952; UP148.001.002.00012 (Box Volume 2)
  - November, 1952 -- 1953; UP148.001.002.00013 (Box Volume 2)
  - March, 1952 -- 1953; UP148.001.002.00014 (Box Volume 2)
  - May, 1952 -- 1953; UP148.001.002.00015 (Box Volume 2)
  - November, 1953 -- 1954; UP148.001.002.00016 (Box Volume 2)
  - January, 1953 -- 1954; UP148.001.002.00017 (Box Volume 2)
  - March, 1953 -- 1954; UP148.001.002.00018 (Box Volume 2)
  - April, 1953 -- 1954; UP148.001.002.00019 (Box Volume 2)
  - November, 1954 -- 1955; UP148.001.002.00020 (Box Volume 2)
  - April, 1954 -- 1955; UP148.001.002.00021 (Box Volume 2)
  - January, 1954 -- 1955; UP148.001.002.00022 (Box Volume 2)
  - November, 1955 -- 1956; UP148.001.002.00023 (Box Volume 2)
  - January, 1955 -- 1956; UP148.001.002.00024 (Box Volume 2)
  - April, 1955 -- 1956; UP148.001.002.00025 (Box Volume 2)
  - November, 1956 -- 1957; UP148.001.002.00026 (Box Volume 2)
  - January, 1957 -- 1958; UP148.001.002.00027 (Box Volume 2)
  - April, 1957 -- 1958; UP148.001.002.00028 (Box Volume 2)
  - November, 1957 -- 1958; UP148.001.002.00029 (Box Volume 2)
  - December, 1957 -- 1958; UP148.001.002.00030 (Box Volume 2)
  - April, 1957 -- 1958; UP148.001.002.00031 (Box Volume 2)
  - November, 1958 -- 1959; UP148.001.002.00032 (Box Volume 2)
  - March, 1958 -- 1959; UP148.001.002.00033 (Box Volume 2)
  - April, 1958 -- 1959; UP148.001.002.00034 (Box Volume 2)
  - November, 1959 -- 1960; UP148.001.002.00035 (Box Volume 2)
  - December, 1959 -- 1960; UP148.001.002.00036 (Box Volume 2)
  - March, 1959 -- 1960; UP148.001.002.00037 (Box Volume 2)
  - April, 1959 -- 1960; UP148.001.002.00038 (Box Volume 2)
  - November, 1960 -- 1961; UP148.001.002.00039 (Box Volume 2)
  - December, 1960 -- 1961; UP148.001.002.00040 (Box Volume 2)
  - April, 1960 -- 1961; UP148.001.002.00042 (Box Volume 2)
  - October, 1961 -- 1962; UP148.001.002.00043 (Box Volume 2)
  - December, 1961 -- 1962; UP148.001.002.00044 (Box Volume 2)
  - March, 1961 -- 1962; UP148.001.002.00045 (Box Volume 2)
  - October, 1962 -- 1963; UP148.001.002.00046 (Box Volume 2)
  - November, 1962 -- 1963; UP148.001.002.00047 (Box Volume 2)
  - March, 1962 -- 1963; UP148.001.002.00048 (Box Volume 2)
  - October, 1963 -- 1964; UP148.001.002.00049 (Box Volume 2)
  - December, 1963 -- 1964; UP148.001.002.00050 (Box Volume 2)
  - Prologue, March, 1964; UP148.001.003.00001 (Box 3)
  - Prologue, October, 1964; UP148.001.003.00002 (Box 3)
  - Prologue, December, 1964; UP148.001.003.00003 (Box 3)
  - Prologue, February, 1965; UP148.001.003.00004 (Box 3)
  - Prologue, April, 1965; UP148.001.003.00005 (Box 3)
  - Prologue, October, 1965; UP148.001.003.00006 (Box 3)
  - Prologue, December, 1965 -- 1966; UP148.001.003.00007 (Box 3)
  - Prologue, February, 1966; UP148.001.003.00008 (Box 3)
  - Prologue, April, 1966; UP148.001.003.00009 (Box 3)
  - Prologue, October, 1966; UP148.001.003.00010 (Box 3)
  - Prologue, December, 1966; UP148.001.003.00011 (Box 3)
  - Prologue, April, 1967; UP148.001.003.00012 (Box 3)
  - Prologue, October, 1967; UP148.001.003.00013 (Box 3)
  - Prologue, March, 1968; UP148.001.003.00014 (Box 3)
  - Prologue, April, 1968; UP148.001.003.00015 (Box 3)
  - Prologue, November, 1968; UP148.001.003.00016 (Box 3)
  - Prologue, February, 1969; UP148.001.003.00017 (Box 3)
  - Prologue, April, 1969; UP148.001.003.00018 (Box 3)
  - Prologue, October, 1969; UP148.001.003.00019 (Box 3)
  - Prologue, December, 1969; UP148.001.003.00020 (Box 3)
  - Prologue, March, 1970; UP148.001.003.00021 (Box 3)
  - Prologue, May, 1970; UP148.001.003.00022 (Box 3)
  - Prologue, October, 1970; UP148.001.003.00023 (Box 3)
  - Prologue, November, 1970; UP148.001.003.00024 (Box 3)
  - Prologue, March, 1971; UP148.001.003.00025 (Box 3)
  - Prologue, May, 1971; UP148.001.003.00026 (Box 3)
  - Prologue, October, 1971; UP148.001.003.00027 (Box 3)
  - Prologue, November, 1971; UP148.001.003.00028 (Box 3)
  - Prologue, March, 1972; UP148.001.003.00029 (Box 3)
  - Prologue, May, 1972; UP148.001.003.00030 (Box 3)
  - Prologue, November, 1972; UP148.001.003.00031 (Box 3)
  - Prologue, April, 1973; UP148.001.003.00032 (Box 3)
  - Prologue, October, 1973; UP148.001.003.00033 (Box 3)
  - Prologue, November, 1973; UP148.001.003.00034 (Box 3)
  - Prologue, March, 1974; UP148.001.003.00035 (Box 3)
  - Prologue, May, 1974; UP148.001.003.00036 (Box 3)
  - Prologue, October, 1974; UP148.001.003.00037 (Box 3)
  - Prologue, November, 1974; UP148.001.003.00038 (Box 3)
  - Prologue, February, 1975; UP148.001.003.00039 (Box 3)
  - Prologue, April, 1975; UP148.001.003.00040 (Box 3)
  - Prologue, October, 1975; UP148.001.003.00041 (Box 3)
  - Prologue, March, 1976; UP148.001.003.00042 (Box 3)
  - Prologue, November, 1976; UP148.001.003.00043 (Box 3)
  - Prologue, December, 1976; UP148.001.003.00044 (Box 3)
  - Prologue, March, 1977; UP148.001.003.00045 (Box 3)
  - Prologue, April, 1977; UP148.001.003.00046 (Box 3)
  - Prologue, October, 1977; UP148.001.003.00047 (Box 3)
  - Prologue, December, 1977; UP148.001.003.00048 (Box 3)
  - Prologue, March, 1978; UP148.001.003.00049 (Box 3)
  - Prologue, April, 1978; UP148.001.003.00050 (Box 3)
  - Prologue, October, 1978; UP148.001.003.00051 (Box 3)
  - Prologue, December, 1978; UP148.001.003.00052 (Box 3)
  - Prologue, February, 1979; UP148.001.003.00053 (Box 3)
  - Prologue, April, 1979; UP148.001.003.00054 (Box 3)
  - Prologue, October, 1979; UP148.001.003.00055 (Box 3)
  - Prologue, December, 1979; UP148.001.003.00056 (Box 3)
  - Prologue, March, 1980; UP148.001.003.00057 (Box 3)
  - Prologue, April, 1980; UP148.001.003.00058 (Box 3)
  - Prologue, October, 1980; UP148.001.003.00059 (Box 3)
  - Prologue, December, 1980; UP148.001.003.00060 (Box 3)
  - Prologue, February, 1981; UP148.001.003.00061 (Box 3)
  - Prologue, May, 1981; UP148.001.003.00062 (Box 3)
  - Prologue, October, 1981; UP148.001.003.00063 (Box 3)
  - Prologue, December, 1981; UP148.001.003.00064 (Box 3)
  - Prologue, March, 1982; UP148.001.003.00065 (Box 3)
  - Prologue, May, 1982; UP148.001.003.00066 (Box 3)
  - Prologue, October, 1982; UP148.001.003.00067 (Box 3)
  - Prologue, December, 1982; UP148.001.003.00068 (Box 3)
  - Prologue, March, 1983; UP148.001.003.00069 (Box 3)
  - Prologue, May, 1983; UP148.001.003.00070 (Box 3)
  - Prologue, October, 1983; UP148.001.003.00071 (Box 3)
  - Prologue, December, 1983; UP148.001.003.00072 (Box 3)
  - Prologue, March, 1984; UP148.001.003.00073 (Box 3)
  - Prologue, April, 1984; UP148.001.003.00074 (Box 3)
  - Prologue, October, 1984; UP148.001.003.00075 (Box 3)
  - Prologue, December, 1984; UP148.001.003.00076 (Box 3)
  - Prologue, February, 1985; UP148.001.003.00077 (Box 3)
  - Prologue, April, 1985; UP148.001.003.00078 (Box 3)
  - Prologue, October, 1985; UP148.001.003.00079 (Box 3)
  - Prologue, November, 1985; UP148.001.003.00080 (Box 3)
  - Prologue, February, 1986; UP148.001.003.00081 (Box 3)
  - Prologue, April, 1986; UP148.001.003.00082 (Box 3)
  - Prologue, October, 1986; UP148.001.003.00083 (Box 3)
  - Prologue, December, 1986; UP148.001.003.00084 (Box 3)
  - Prologue, February, 1987; UP148.001.003.00085 (Box 3)
  - Prologue, April, 1987; UP148.001.003.00086 (Box 3)
  - Prologue, October, 1987; UP148.001.003.00087 (Box 3)
  - Prologue, December, 1987; UP148.001.003.00088 (Box 3)
  - Prologue, February, 1988; UP148.001.003.00089 (Box 3)
  - Prologue, April, 1988; UP148.001.003.00090 (Box 3)
  - Prologue, October, 1988; UP148.001.003.00091 (Box 3)
  - Prologue, December, 1988; UP148.001.003.00092 (Box 3)
  - Prologue, February, 1989; UP148.001.003.00093 (Box 3)
  - Prologue, April, 1989; UP148.001.003.00094 (Box 3)
  - Prologue, October, 1989; UP148.001.003.00095 (Box 3)
  - Prologue, December, 1989; UP148.001.003.00096 (Box 3)
  - Prologue, February, 1990; UP148.001.004.00001 (Box 4)
  - Prologue, April, 1990; UP148.001.004.00002 (Box 4)
  - Prologue, October, 1990; UP148.001.004.00003 (Box 4)
  - Prologue, December, 1990; UP148.001.004.00004 (Box 4)
  - Prologue, April, 1991; UP148.001.004.00005 (Box 4)
  - Prologue, October, 1991; UP148.001.004.00006 (Box 4)
  - Prologue, February, 1992; UP148.001.004.00007 (Box 4)
  - Prologue, April, 1992; UP148.001.004.00008 (Box 4)
  - Prologue, October, 1992; UP148.001.004.00009 (Box 4)
  - Prologue, February, 1993; UP148.001.004.00010 (Box 4)
  - Prologue, April, 1993; UP148.001.004.00011 (Box 4)
  - Prologue, October, 1993; UP148.001.004.00012 (Box 4)
  - Prologue, February, 1994; UP148.001.004.00013 (Box 4)
  - Prologue, April, 1994; UP148.001.004.00014 (Box 4)
  - Prologue, October, 1994; UP148.001.004.00015 (Box 4)
  - Prologue, February, 1995; UP148.001.004.00016 (Box 4)
  - Prologue, April, 1995; UP148.001.004.00017 (Box 4)
  - Prologue, October, 1995; UP148.001.004.00018 (Box 4)
  - Prologue, February, 1996; UP148.001.004.00019 (Box 4)
  - Prologue, April, 1996; UP148.001.004.00020 (Box 4)
  - Prologue, October, 1996; UP148.001.004.00021 (Box 4)
  - Prologue,February, 1997; UP148.001.004.00022 (Box 4)
  - Prologue, April, 1997; UP148.001.004.00023 (Box 4)
  - Prologue, October, 1997; UP148.001.004.00024 (Box 4)
  - Prologue, February, 1998; UP148.001.004.00025 (Box 4)
  - Prologue, April, 1998; UP148.001.004.00026 (Box 4)
  - Prologue, October, 1998; UP148.001.004.00027 (Box 4)
  - Prologue, February, 1999; UP148.001.004.00028 (Box 4)
  - Prologue, April, 1999; UP148.001.004.00029 (Box 4)
  - Prologue, October, 1999; UP148.001.004.00030 (Box 4)
  - Prologue, February, 2000; UP148.001.004.00031 (Box 4)
  - Prologue, April, 2000; UP148.001.004.00032 (Box 4)
  - Prologue, October, 2000; UP148.001.004.00033 (Box 4)
  - Prologue, February, 2001; UP148.001.004.00034 (Box 4)
  - Prologue, April, 2001; UP148.001.004.00035 (Box 4)
  - Prologue, October, 2001; UP148.001.004.00036 (Box 4)
  - Prologue, February, 2002; UP148.001.004.00037 (Box 4)
  - Prologue, April, 2002; UP148.001.004.00038 (Box 4)
  - Prologue, October, 2002; UP148.001.004.00039 (Box 4)
  - Prologue, February, 2003; UP148.001.004.00040 (Box 4)
  - Prologue, April, 2003; UP148.001.004.00041 (Box 4)
  - Prologue, October, 2003; UP148.001.004.00042 (Box 4)
  - Prologue, February, 2004; UP148.001.004.00043 (Box 4)
  - Prologue, April, 2004; UP148.001.004.00044 (Box 4)
  - Prologue, October, 2004; UP148.001.004.00045 (Box 4)
  - Prologue, February, 2005; UP148.001.004.00046 (Box 4)
  - Prologue, April, 2005; UP148.001.004.00047 (Box 4)
  - Prologue, October, 2005; UP148.001.004.00048 (Box 4)
  - Prologue, February, 2006; UP148.001.004.00049 (Box 4)
  - Prologue, April, 2006; UP148.001.004.00050 (Box 4)